♪♪
For you, dear Ben.
Thank you.
Won't you come in?
Diana, you look, uh, different.
You mean serene? Tranquil?
Yeah. What happened?
I've just spent six days
at the Anona Retreat...
Yoga, relaxation,
deep breathing.
Anger out, tranquility in.
Life's too short to
manifest anger, Ben.
It's just... It's just wonderful
how sometimes a misfortune
can turn a whole life around.
How wise you are, dear Ben.
So how's my case coming along?
Slow, Diana, slow.
We don't have a shred of proof
as to who killed your husband.
But you will, won't
you, Ben dear?
I hope so, Diana.
I hope so, but I have to
admit right now I'm stumped.
But I'm not paying you a small
fortune to be stumped, Ben dear.
I'm paying you to prove that
I didn't kill that philandering...
I'm trying my best.
Breathe, breathe in.
Tranquil. Breathe. Tranquil.
Don't patronize me, you...
You old... you old jackass!
Many 30 years in the
slammer is what you need!
Randy came by when
she heard about Jack.
Yeah, well, when Jack came
by, Caroline was in a meeting,
but Jack just barged right in, talked
to her for, I'd say, about 30 seconds,
and then he came out again.
But on his way out,
he made this remark
that sounded like Caroline
was selling the clients a Warhol.
See, Jack told me that the picture in
Caroline's office showed... get this...
Six rows of $50 bills.
See, Warhol painted
a huge $1.00 bill,
but I have never heard
of him painting a lot of 50s.
Besides that, I went ahead and checked
the sales and the purchase records.
We haven't handled a
Warhol in over two years.
Well, tell him
the rest. Tell him.
Well, a few minutes after Jack left,
Caroline came out of the conference room,
and she was really upset, and so
were the guys she was meeting with.
Remember their names?
Mm-hmm. Carl
Shepley and Dick Lerner.
- Carl Shepley?
- Yeah. Do you know him?
Those are the three people
that John Resnick called
- the night before he was murdered.
- Hmm.
Well, yeah, you know, they're
at the art gallery all the time.
That's why I really couldn't
understand why Caroline got so upset.
Ever heard of an artist
named Hugo Wykoff?
Oh, I have. We handled
his lithographs at the gallery.
He was killed in a
hit-and-run about a year ago.
That's right.
♪♪
Excuse me.
Excuse me!
I'm looking for Lilly Wykoff.
Oh, that's me.
Can I ask you something?
What do you call all this?
This is... It's art,
that's what it is.
It's art.
My name is Conrad McMasters.
I'm a private investigator.
I wonder if I could ask you a couple
of questions about your late husband.
What about my husband?
I understand he was
a wonderful artist.
He was a great artist, my Hugo.
Here, sit down.
Uh, did he ever tell you about
anybody named John Resnick?
That's the man who killed him.
Killed him?
He commissioned Hugo
to do some work for him.
Now, I don't know what kind
of work; Hugo wouldn't say.
But I do know they had a
big fight on the phone one day,
and when Hugo hung
up, he was scared.
Two days later, he was dead.
The police tell me John
Resnick had an airtight alibi.
Well, I don't care. He's the
one who ran Hugo down.
Did Hugo ever mention
anybody named Carl Shepley?
No.
What about Caroline
Westlake or Dick Lerner?
Sure, he mentioned them.
Caroline had his work
on display in her gallery,
and Dick Lerner bought
one of his best pieces.
That was the last thing Hugo
sold before he was killed.
Did you happen to save
some of your husband's art?
I saved all of it.
Could I see it?
Sure.
Oh, the nudes are
all of me, by the way.
Uh, Mr. Shepley?
Hi. I'm Ben Matlock.
I'm glad I finally
caught up with you.
I've got to call you back, boss.
What's this about, Mr. Matlock?
Well, I represent the woman who's
accused of killing Jack Huntington,
and your name keeps
popping up all over the place.
- You're kidding me.
- Yeah.
You're friends with John Resnick,
Caroline Westlake, and Dick Lerner.
Were you in business with them?
Yeah. I'm a broker.
I bring people who want
to buy things together
with the people who
want to sell them...
Classic cars, artwork,
real estate, dental practices.
I'm kind of a
professional middleman.
Oh. That's good.
What's going on here?
Well, all I know so far for sure
is that John Resnick was involved
in a murder about a year ago
and that he called you
at 2:00 in the morning
the night before he was killed.
He also called Caroline Westlake
and Dick Lerner that same night,
and they are the two people
that Jack Huntington saw you with
when he came barging into the
conference room at the gallery
the night before
he was murdered.
And since you seem to be at the
center of all this death and destruction,
I was hoping you could
tell me what's going on.
Mr. Matlock, I would like to help
you, but I don't know what to tell you.
Maybe you could tell me
what you and Ms. Westlake and
Mr. Lerner were looking at that night.
What night?
The night Jack Huntington come
bursting into that conference room.
Now, that was business, Mr. Matlock.
I'd just as soon not discuss that.
How about the next
morning around, oh, say, 8:00,
when Jack Huntington was killed?
Could we discuss
that, or is that business?
If memory serves, I
was playing racquetball.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
Mr. Matlock, I have places to go.
Uh, one more question...
The Hillsdale Racquet Club.
He knows about John Resnick?
My God, what else does he know?
- Nothing.
- What if he followed you?
- He didn't.
- Are you sure?
Hey, I ought to know if the
guy I've been tailing for two days
has been tailing
me, don't you think?
So we're going to
go through with it?
You'd better believe we are.
Within 24 hours, the three of us
are going to get an awful lot of money.
See, Hugo dated his lithographs.
This is what he was
working on when he died.
The man knew how to
draw money, didn't he?
Right down to the
whiskers on Grant's face.
Yeah.
Jack saw something
he shouldn't have seen,
and Caroline and Carl Shepley
and Dick Lerner were afraid
he might figure out what it was,
and so they simply killed him.
Good morning, Randy.
Oh, hi, Mr. Shepley.
She's waiting for you
in the conference room.
Great.
Don't forget the
baseboards, okay?
- Right.
- Thanks.
Caroline, what the
hell is wrong with you?
What's he doing here?
- Who?
- Shh.
The guy in the coveralls.
He's a janitor. He's cleaning.
The hell he is. That's Ben
Matlock's private investigator.
I saw him outside his house.
All right, I'm going to
pick the truck up at 3:00,
and I should be able to
make delivery by 4:30.
So by 7:00 it will all be over.
Yeah.
So the poor guy started to
run up on the grass to get away,
but the car went right after
him and just nailed him.
About how far away from the
decedent were you when this happened?
Oh, 30-40 feet.
Were you close enough to
see the car's license plate?
Oh, yes, easily.
- Do you remember it?
- You bet.
It was ESV 57I.
Georgia plates.
Oh, and there was a frame around
the plate saying "Born to Shop."
Did you happen to
notice the make of the car?
Yeah. It was a blue
Lincoln Mark VII.
Since it's been stipulated that
the defendant, Diana Huntington,
owns a blue Lincoln Mark VII,
license plate number ESV 571,
I have no further questions.
- Mr. Matlock?
- Yes, sir.
Uh, this car that
drove past you,
did you get a
look at the driver?
Well, no, not a
real good look, no.
So the only view you had of the
car and its driver was from behind?
Right.
From behind, what
did the driver look like?
Well, I was so busy memorizing the plate
that I didn't look at the driver at all.
Oh, so you saw Diana Huntington's
car, but you didn't see who was driving it?
Right.
It could have been anybody.
Yes, absolutely.
Thank you.
Miss Sullivan, Jack
Huntington was living with you
at the time of his
death, is that correct?
Yes.
He had recently
separated from his wife?
That's right.
Wouldn't it be more accurate to say
that he was hiding from Diana Huntington?
I couldn't really say.
Well, didn't Jack Huntington
give specific instructions
to both his attorney
and his accountant
to withhold his whereabouts
from the defendant?
Yes.
He was afraid of his wife's
violent temper, wasn't he?
Objection. Calls
for speculation.
Sustained.
Did Diana Huntington send a birthday
card to her husband through her attorney?
Yes.
Did you happen to see that card?
Oh, I sure did.
And what did it say?
It said, "Happy birthday,
dear. Wish you were dead."
That was a joke!
It was a joke!
Order. Mr. Matlock,
restrain your client.
Sit down, Diana.
It was a joke. Aren't you
going to say something?
Miss Sullivan,
did the defendant recently visit you
and Jack Huntington at your home?
Yes.
How would you characterize her state
of mind when she entered your house?
She... She was upset.
Upset?
Didn't she burst through
your front door flailing a gun?
That gun wasn't
loaded, you cretin.
Would you get off your
duff and say something?
Diana... Quiet. I'll
hold you in contempt.
Do you call this justice?
Quiet!
Oh, God, no.
No. Please don't.
Um, I'm not armed.
I had no control over the
prosecutor's questions today, Diana.
I know that.
I just answered them honestly.
I know that, too, Lisa.
I don't want to talk about
what happened in court today.
I just want to ask you
something. Could I come in?
Mm. So this is how artists live.
I'm comfortable with it.
So was Jack.
Oh, my gosh.
Did you know that I knit this for
Jack with my own hands 15 years ago?
I'm glad to see he held
on to something of mine.
Do you knit?
No. My mother does.
Diana, you wanted to talk
to me about something?
Yes.
I don't know why this is
important to me, but it is.
Were you going to marry Jack?
That's your question?
I don't know. We
never talked about it.
Oh, come on.
Two people who are presumably in
love talk to each other about their future.
Yeah, we did, just
not in those terms.
I don't know what you mean.
Getting married
wasn't important to me.
I just wanted to be
with Jack, that's all.
Huh.
Marriage was important
to your generation.
My generation?
Look, Diana, I
don't want to fight.
You and me, we're different.
Oh, we sure are.
No, this is wrong.
I loved Jack, and I
guess you did, too.
In our very different
way, we'll both miss him.
Trevor Bone, bring up
number 16. It's the white van.
The coast couldn't be clearer.
Where's Charles Beckman?
A million.
Now we see what you've got.
Ten million in 50s.
Hold it.
This one.
Okay, Charlie.
One thousand percent
return on your money.
You can't beat that.
Beats the hell out of a
two-year CD, that's for sure.
I'll be in touch.
Hold it right there!
Nobody move!
We just got done
searching the room
you leased in that
industrial park, Mr. Lerner.
We had a warrant,
of course, counselor.
We found a printing
press and two plates...
One for the front of a $50
bill and one for the back.
Who made the plates for you?
My clients have nothing to say.
Was it Hugo Wykoff?
We also have the whole transaction between
you and Charles Beckman on videotape.
In other words, we've
got you dead to rights.
So why don't you save the
taxpayers of this state a lot of money
and maybe yourselves some prison
time and fill us in on all the details?
I told you, my clients have
nothing to say, Lieutenant.
Well, well, Mr. Shepley.
Pull up a chair.
Glad you could join us.
I take it you've been
advised of your rights?
My lawyer's on his way.
We've been sitting here
discussing this counterfeiting ring...
You mean you were just
discussing this alleged ring.
The three of you
are involved with.
If you'll recall, my
clients have said nothing.
Well, they'd better
say something
because we're not just
talking about counterfeit here.
We're talking about murder,
and that's a capital offense.
And one or all of you could
be spending some time...
And I'm not talking about
some federal country club.
I'm talking about hard time.
State prison.
And I'm not talking
about two or three years.
I'm talking about
the rest of your lives.
My clients have nothing to
say on that subject, either.
The hell they don't.
When I started asking questions
about that picture you
dummied up for John Resnick,
you figured you'd better
keep an eye on me, didn't you?
That's how you got onto Conrad.
And that's how you knew Diana
Huntington would be a perfect patsy for you
when you realized you
had to kill her husband.
I insist you stop
this badgering.
One of you stole her
car and ran him down.
I'm as sure of that
as I'm sitting here.
I just don't know
which one... you?
I told you, I was playing
racquetball that morning.
- You?
- Don't answer that.
I was at Chez Sal's
making a sales pitch.
You, where were you
at 8:00 that morning?
You don't have to say anything.
I was in bed.
- Alone?
- Don't answer that!
Yes.
So you can't prove
you were in bed.
And you can't prove I wasn't.
Diana, what are you doing here?
I brought her.
You went and told her
I was making progress.
She followed me
following Shepley.
She blew my cover.
No, I didn't.
What do you call it when the person
you're trying to secretly watch sees you?
Well, I didn't know you had a
cover, so how could I blow it?
Diana, you shouldn't
have followed Conrad.
Oh, please, don't yell at me.
Oh, since when did
you mind yelling?
Well, you know Dr. Dennis
Woodruff, the radio therapist?
I called him yesterday,
and I found out
that my anger is just a cover
for my extreme sensitivity.
Diana, you need therapy, yeah,
but not out of books
or over the radio.
You need a bona fide doctor.
Somebody you can interact with.
You think so?
Oh, yes. Somebody
who can talk sense to you.
Promise me you'll get
a psychiatrist, Diana.
Okay.
And promise me this is the last time
you'll interfere with this investigation.
Interfere? I'm paying
you a fortune for this.
You're working for me.
Diana, do you want
me to stay on this case?
Yes, dear Ben, of course I do.
Then you've got to
stay away from here.
Get a psychiatrist.
Go see him as soon as you
get out of bed in the morning
and stay there
all day, every day.
Now get out of here.
I'm not going to say anything.
I just got to Caroline
Westlake's house, Ben.
Right. I'll let you
know what I find.
Hi.
Hey, are you the guy that usually
reads the meters at this house?
Mm-hmm.
If you've got a problem with your
bill, call the folks downtown, okay?
No, no. I just want to know
how often you come here.
Once a month.
- Always on Wednesdays?
- Yeah.
- Always at 8 in the morning?
Great. By any chance, were you
here on the 18th of last month?
Nope. I was here on the 25th.
Got to get out of here
before the gardener comes.
He always gives me hell when I
step on his petunias or gardenias
or whatever the
hell this stuff is.
Les? Hey, Les?
What?
Where have you been?
When's the big day?
There's not going
to be a big day.
- What happened?
- I don't want to talk about it.
Well, who called it off?
Mildred, the bride-to-be,
that's who called it off.
Why?
I don't want to talk about it.
Oh, Les, tell me what happened.
Okay.
She said if we got married,
she'd lose her Social Security,
so why don't we just be friends and
just go on meeting at the supermarket.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
Just go on meeting
at the supermarket.
What kind of life is that?
Yeah.
Of course, maybe
it's for the best.
I mean, she needs her Social
Security, and you need yours,
so it could be a
blessing in disguise.
Well, it could be.
Yeah. Sure.
And you can always keep on
helping her pick out her Casabas.
Well, yeah, there's that.
Sure.
I understand you were
arrested recently, Ms. Westlake.
Since it's already a
matter of public record,
would you mind telling the
court what the charges were?
On the advice of legal counsel and
in view of my Fifth Amendment rights,
I decline to answer
that question.
Then at this time, I would
like to enter into evidence
this arrest report
that was filed
at the time Ms. Westlake
was taken into custody.
For the record, it charges
the witness, Caroline Westlake,
with the creation and distribution
of counterfeit U.S. currency...
Specifically,
counterfeit $50 bills.
Is that what it
says, Ms. Westlake?
I suppose.
I understand that Jack
Huntington, the night before he died,
walked in unannounced on
a meeting you were having
in your conference
room at your art gallery.
I'm afraid I don't recall.
It was the meeting with
Carl Shepley and Dick Lerner,
the one where you were
showing them that Andy Warhol.
I don't remember
any meeting like that.
Well, your assistant does.
Now, I can put her on
the stand, but if I do,
then the good men
and women of the jury
might get the idea that
you're hiding something.
- Objection.
- Withdrawn.
Are you sure you don't
remember that meeting?
- I guess. Vaguely.
- Vaguely. Okay.
Where Carl Shepley
and Dick Lerner present?
- I think so, yes.
- Mm-hmm.
They were arrested for counterfeiting
at the same time you were, weren't they?
It's public record.
Then I guess they were.
What were you discussing
when Jack walked in on you?
Business. I don't
recall specifics.
Maybe I can help you out.
You were showing your
two friends that Andy Warhol.
I wasn't showing
them any Warhol.
Well, according to your assistant
Randy, Jack told her you were.
He was mistaken.
And according to
Jack's girlfriend,
he said the Warhol he
saw was a sheet of $50 bills.
- That is not true.
- Isn't that some coincidence, though?
I mean, you're showing your
two friends a sheet of 50s,
and a week later, you and these
same two friends are arrested
with a truckload
of counterfeit 50s.
I'd say that's a big
coincidence, wouldn't you?
I choose not to comment on that.
He saw a proof sheet.
A proof sheet.
It was your first run
of 50s off your press.
He saw it, you had to explain what it
was, so you told him it was a Warhol.
But you knew that sooner or
later he'd put 2 and 2 together,
so you stole Diana Huntington's
car and ran Jack down in the street.
- That's a lie!
- Objection!
That's enough, Mr. Matlock.
You're supposed to be questioning
this witness, not testifying in her place.
Objection sustained.
I'll say this just
once: cut it out!
Yes, sir.
Uh, at, uh, at 8:00
the morning of Wednesday
the 18th, last month,
the morning Jack Huntington
was killed, where were you?
I was in bed.
Do you always
sleep in that late?
I'm a night owl.
I rarely go to bed before 1:30 and
even more rarely get up before 9.
That's what Louis said.
Your gardener, Louis Sattoria.
He's sitting right over there.
When he started
taking care of your lawn,
you told him not to do any mowing
till after 9:00 so as not to wake you.
- Is that right?
- Yes.
Does he come every week?
Yes.
- What day?
- Wednesday.
What time?
Around 8, I guess.
I can't say for sure
because I'm never up.
That's not quite true, is it?
Uh, he remembers seeing you driving
away from your house one morning
as he was just
coming up the street.
It stuck in his mind because he had
never seen you up so early before.
It was 7:55.
You know what the date was?
Wednesday the 18th.
Now, you said you were in bed.
Why did you lie?
I didn't lie. I just forgot.
Forgot what?
That I had a
meeting that morning.
With whom?
Jeffrey Aiello.
Who's Jeffrey Aiello?
A businessman. I was
with him till almost 9.
What was the meeting about?
You're going to
have to ask him that.
Why didn't you
tell me this before?
555-1057. That's
Aiello's number.
When you call him,
you'll understand.
No more questions.
Wait up, wait up.
I want you to find out
who Jeffrey Aiello is.
I know him. He's a two-bit hood.
Caroline!
- What are you doing?
- I want...
Get your hands off of me.
I mean it. Stop it. Let go.
Let go of me.
Thanks for coming, Mr. Powell.
Matt, do you want to
get Mr. Powell's car?
- Thank you.
Whoa, talk about a quick
eater. Not good for you.
- Didn't really come to eat.
- Want to get the gentlemen's car?
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you.
Good morning, Mrs.
Holden, Mrs. Roberts.
- Another power breakfast, I see.
- Yes.
Do you know everybody
that comes here?
Most of the regulars I do. It pays
to be friendly in my line of work.
Is Dick Lerner a regular?
Yeah, yeah. Do you
know Mr. Lerner?
- Sort of.
- He comes in every couple of weeks.
Usually has eggs benedict and
leaves with a little bit on his shirt.
That hostess in there said he was here
last month on the morning of the 18th,
but she can't remember
exactly when he got here.
I don't suppose you
have any idea, do you?
No, I wouldn't remember that.
- Why? What's this all about?
- He's a client.
I need to corroborate whether
he was here on the 18th or not.
The 18th? Rings no bells.
Wait a minute, the 18th?
That was the week they were
tearing up the street out there.
Oh, yeah, yeah, I remember now.
He was giving me a hard time because
he couldn't use the front entrance.
He had to come around back, and I was
giving him a hard time about his car again.
What about his car?
He came in a cab. His car
is always breaking down.
He drives a terrible
vehicle. I have a better one.
Mr. Lerner, would you please
tell the court who Jeffrey Aiello is?
I don't know any Jeffrey Aiello.
No?
According to the records we
subpoenaed from the phone company,
he called your office
three times last month.
Then he must have been
trying to sell me something
because I sure
don't remember him.
Jeffrey Aiello did time for passing
counterfeit bank checks a while back.
Did you know that?
Of course not.
He wasn't trying to
sell you something.
He was trying to buy a bunch of
counterfeit money from you, wasn't he?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Only you and your friends got a
better deal from Charles Beckman,
so you told Mr. Aiello to take a
hike... All except Ms. Westlake.
She decided to print
up a few more bills
and do business with
Mr. Aiello after all...
Only secretly, so she
wouldn't have to cut in anybody.
And that's what the fight was about
in the corridor yesterday, wasn't it?
Oh, no, no, no.
And that's what her
meeting with Mr. Aiello was
at the time of the
murder, wasn't it?
How should I know
what Caroline was doing?
You know, the funny thing is
when she double-crossed you,
she gave herself an alibi
for the time of the murder.
And she has one,
but you don't, do you?
I was at Chez Sal's
with a prospective client.
Is that how you got
those cuts on your arm?
Would you mind
pushing up your sleeve?
Push it up. Push it up.
These are not cuts, they're
scratches. I got them pruning my roses.
They didn't come from roses.
They came from this car.
Diana Huntington's car.
You stole it and used
it to kill her husband.
That's not true.
But you sideswiped a
post during the killing,
and the window on the
driver's side shattered,
and glass came flying through, all
over your arm and, look, even up here.
And that's how
you got those cuts.
Objection. This is all
speculation, Your Honor.
And where is it leading?
Mr. Matlock, you have
a knack for storytelling.
Where is it leading?
It's leading to reasonable
doubt, Your Honor.
Reasonable doubt that
my client killed her husband.
- Proceed.
- Thank you.
Now we were talking about
where you got those cuts.
I was at a business meeting at Chez
Sal's that morning from 8 till almost 9:30.
You got those cuts
in a restaurant?
No, from my roses.
Oh.
How did you get
to that restaurant?
I drove.
You sure you didn't come by cab?
Yes.
Well, the doorman at
Chez Sal's said you did.
He's right. My car broke
down. I called a cab.
I was mistaken.
So you were late
for your meeting?
- A little, yes.
- Yeah.
The Red and White Cab Company says they
didn't pick you up till well after 8:30.
So you were not at the
restaurant at the time of the murder.
I was trying to get there.
They said they picked
you up at a gas station.
Yes. I had my car towed
there so they could work on it.
- Towed from where?
- My house.
- Who towed it?
- I don't remember.
Wally's Garage.
I have the work
order right here.
See?
You paid cash and
gave a phony name.
Why did you do that, Mr. Lerner?
I didn't. Obviously you've
got the wrong work order.
Well, this is your license
plate number, isn't it?
They wrote it down.
They also wrote down the location
of your car when they picked it up.
See? 17000 block of Cortez
Avenue. Is that where you live?
There must be some mistake.
No. No. You know where that is?
It's right around the corner
from Diana Huntington's house.
You parked there,
walked up to her house,
stole her car from her garage,
used it to kill her
husband, then put it back.
Then walked around
the corner to you car.
It wouldn't start, so
you used your car phone
and called Wally's Garage,
the closest one you could find,
and they towed you
to that gas station.
And from there you went by
cab to the restaurant, didn't you?
All because Jack Huntington
walked in on that meeting
and inadvertently saw
that sheet of counterfeit 50s.
He'd already been making waves,
asking questions about that
photograph the three of you fabricated
to give John Resnick an
alibi for Hugo Wykoff's murder.
Then sometime later, for whatever your
reason, one of you killed John Resnick.
Maybe it was you, Mr. Lerner.
It was one of you,
that I'm sure of.
And pretty soon the police
will figure out which one.
Counterfeiting is against
the law, Mr. Lerner,
but killing three people... And
one of them... Jack Huntington...
Just in your way,
kind of like a fly.
Nothing further.
We find the defendant,
Diana Huntington, not guilty.
Thank you, ladies and
gentlemen of the jury.
Thank you one and
all. Court is adjourned.
Diana, Diana, Diana.
I'm glad everything
turned out all right.
Thank you.
Listen, I promised you that I
would get into therapy, and I will.
I never go back on my
bargains, even when I'm mad.
Good. Good. Great.
- Would you do me a favor?
- No.
I beg your pardon?
Doing you a favor is what got
us into this mess in the first place.
I should have said no the first time,
and it's this time definitely no. No.
Well, I was going to ask
you to loan me your pen
so I could write a
check for your fee,
but if that's the way you
feel, then the hell with you.
www.tvsubtitles.net